＜ナルト：航海日誌　補足。
Ship’s log, supplemental entry.
これで５日連続の嵐だ。
This is the fifth consecutive day
of the storm.
船を転覆させないため
乗員総出の大忙し＞
Every man on deck is
working hard
to keep the ship from capsizing.
（ガイ）うぅ…　うっ！
＜　でも俺には　頼れる仲間たちが
いたのであった＞
And I had friends
I could count on.
いっけ～　分身ども！
Go, clones!
♪～
Here you go!
Here!
これで最後だ。
This is the last of it!
しゃ～！
終わったぜ。
It's over! Good work!
ご苦労さん　今　術を解くからな。
I'll release the jutsu now.
フゥ～　やっと休めるってばよぉ。
We can finally rest!
（ヤマト）ナルト！
マストが風で持ってかれそうだ。
Naruto!
We're about to lose
the mast to the wind!
分身たちとロープを支えてくれ！
了解！　すぐ向かうってばよ。
Can you go and support
the rope with your clones?
Got it! We'll get on it right away!
え～っ！　まだ働かせんのかよ～。
– What?!
You're going to make us
work some more?!
今は猫の手も…　いや
分身の手も借りたい時なんだ。
Right now, we need every hand
that's available.
So come on, get to work!
さぁ　働いた働いた！
Do your best, me!
頑張れ～　俺！
いくら分身だからって
あんまりだってばよぉ～！
Even if we're clones,
this is too much!
あぁ～っ！
なんか　危ないってばよ。
That looks dangerous.
誰か
上に上がって調べてこいよ。
Someone go up there
and check it out.
おい。
お前が行けってば。
Hey, you go.
俺は疲れてんだよ。
I'm tired.
みんな疲れてるってばよ。
We're all tired!
The fatigue I feel is different
from what you clones feel.
分身と本体は疲れ方が違うだろ。
んな話　初耳だ。
I've never heard that before.
リーダーとしての重みが違うんだよ。
My burden as the leader
is heavier.
誰が　リーダーって決めた？
Who made you our leader?
何だと！？
だいたい何だよ！
What did you say?!
It's not fair.
徹夜徹夜で俺たちをコキ使って！
You kept us up on numerous
all-night watches
そんで
ようやく嵐が去ったってのに→
and when the storm finally passes,
多重影分身の術を
解かないなんてよ！
you refuse to release
the Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu?
どういうつもりだ！？
また嵐になったら→
What’s up with that?
If there's another storm,
we’ll need your help again.
お前たちに働いてもらわなきゃ
ならねえんだからよぉ。
待て…　こら　もう…。
Hey wait... Hey you...
ふざけんな！
俺たちを何だと思ってんだ！？
That's enough! Just who do you
think we are anyway?
俺の分身だ！
Clones of me!
お前たちは俺の言うとおりに
動いてればいいんだよ。
You just have to do
exactly as I say!
なっ　何だと！？
やめろ！
W-What?!
Forget him!
分身にも信頼されねえ本体なんか
放っておけ。
Don't bother with someone
like that.
He doesn't even have
the trust of his own clones.
こっちだって　分身相手に
ムキになるほど→
Well, I’m not foolish enough to
take you clones seriously.
バカじゃねえってんだ！
まったく
本体風情が偉そうにしやがって。
Damn it.
Who the hell do you think you are?
いいか？
分身あってのお前じゃねえか。
Listen. You owe everything
to your clones.
風遁を覚えたのも
俺たちのおかげだ。
Remember, you learned
your Wind Style thanks to us.
ふざけるな！
あれは　俺の実力だ！
You've got to be kidding!
That power is my very own!
なんだと？
What?!
なんか　お前ら
さっきまでと雰囲気違くないか？
You guys...
It kind of seems like you guys
changed a bit from a while ago.
フン　お前が今まで
俺たち分身一人ひとりと→
It just goes to show that
you haven't had a one-on-one
relationship with your clones.
いかに向き合ってこなかったか
ってことだ。
つまり　分身とはいえ　ムラというか
偏りができちゃうんだなぁ。
In other words, we're your clones.
But you have this bias,
this prejudice towards us.
偏りっていうか→
It's not bias.
俺の中に存在するとは
思えないやつもいるってばよ。
It's just hard to accept that
some of you guys are inside me.
あら　やだ　自己否定？
Oh dear.
Are you criticizing yourself?
お前みたいな
なよっち～いのとか→
There’s no way a softie
like you or
こんな湿っぽいの
俺ん中には　いねえっての！
a gloomy one like you
are a part of me!
分身しても
自分って見えないもんなのね。
I guess you don't recognize
yourself in your clones.
そっちの気がなかったら→
If you didn’t have
this personality inside you,
お色気の術とか
さまになんねえし→
you wouldn’t need a jutsu
like the Sexy Jutsu.
あんな術　ほんとは
恥ずかしかったけど→
To be honest, that jutsu
is really embarrassing.
寂しかったから
誰かに　かまってほしくて…。
But I was lonely and
wanted someone to pay
attention to me.
泣くなって！
昔のことだってばよ！
Don't cry! It's all in the past.
今じゃ　里のみんなに
チ～ヤホヤされて→
Now, everyone in the village
makes such a fuss over us.
ハッピー　ハッピー！
やめろ！
Be happy! Be happy!
Cut it out!
お前ら　うざい！　お望みどおり
術を解いてやるってばよ。
You guys are irritating me!
Fine! If that's what you want,
I'll release the jutsu.
冗談じゃねえ。
Stop joking.
どうせまた　コキ使われんだ。
こうなりゃ居座ってやる。
You'll probably work us
to the bone anyway.
Like it or not, we're staying!
しばらく反省してろ！　解！
You need to cool your head
and repent!
Release!
ポーン！　わぁ～　消えた～。
Bang!
We're fading.
な…　なんで消えないってば…。
How come you guys
aren’t disappearing?
解！
Release!
解！　解　解…　解！　か～い！
Release! Release! Release! Release!
Release! Release! Release!
Release!
解けねえ。
It's not working.
知らなかったのかよ。
分身を出すのも解くのも→
Didn't you know?
Summoning and releasing
clones all depend
俺たちの
同意あってのことなんだよ。
on the willingness of
the clones themselves.
お　お前ら…。
とっつかまえろ！
Y-You guys...
Capture him!
わっ　やめろ！　こら　放せ～！
Yikes! Stop!
Hey! Let go of me!
殴られて
消滅するのは勘弁だからな。
We're not gonna let you hit us
and extinguish us!
縛り上げるぞ！
お～っ！
Tie him up!
– Right!
何やってるんだ？　ナルト。
– What are you doing, Naruto?
– Oww! That hurts!
Come on guys!
Get away from me!
おっ　いいぞ！
熱き血潮をたぎらせ→
Hey, this is great!
Passionate, hot-blooded men
fighting, colliding,
ぶつかり合う男たち。
嫌いじゃない。
releasing pent-up energy!
（アオバ）そんな雰囲気じゃ
なさそうですけど…。
That doesn’t seem like
that’s the case here.
た…　助けてくれ　ヤマト隊長。
Help, Captain Yamato!
この船は
俺たち　ナルト組が占拠した！
We, the Naruto Gang,
are taking control of this ship!
こいつは人質だ！
He's our hostage!
ナルトの命を助けたければ
俺たちの要求に無条件で従え！
If you want Naruto to live,
you must agree to our demands
unconditionally!
え？　ど…　どういうことだい？
W-What's going on?!
ねぇ　みんな…　１時の方向に
島影が見えるってば～。
Hey everyone, I can see
the silhouette of an island at one o'clock.
どれどれ？
Let's see.
ふむ　我々の画策を
実行に移すには　もってこいだ。
This fits perfectly into our plans.
よ～し　あの島へ舵を取れ！
All right! Sail to that island!
どうしますか？
What'll we do?
I can't believe the clones would
actually take Naruto's life!
分身たちが　ナルトの命を
本当に　とるとは思えん。
しかし　俺も陸地で休みたいしな。
Still, I could use
some rest on dry land.
は？
ようそろ～！
Straight ahead!
（ヤマト／アオバ）ようそろ～。
– Straight ahead.
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
Revenge of the Shadow Clones
[スピーカ]あ～　あ～。
我々の　分身環境の向上！
MEET OUR DEMANDS
We clones seek improvements
in our work environment!
We demand compensation
and security
ならびに　危険手当や補償などの
要求を聞き入れるまで→
for the risks we take!
我ら分身労働者の
当然の権利として→
And until these
demands are met,
we, the clone workforce,
will go on strike!
ストライキを決行する！
食事のメニュー改善も　よろしくね。
Oh, don't forget about
improving our meals.
ラーメン食わせろ～　バカ野郎！
We want ramen too, you idiot!
とんこつ味噌チャーシューね～！
さすが本体。
Miso-flavored pork stock
with roast pork!
Now you're talking, Real Naruto!
わかってんじゃねえかよ。
フン！
我々の満足のいく回答を
得られるまで→
Until we get
a satisfactory settlement,
お前たちには
その島で待機してもらう。
you guys can wait on that island!
やっかいなことに
なってしまいましたね。
What a disturbing turn of events.
万一　ストが長引いて　これ以上
スケジュールが遅れてしまったら→
If the strike drags on and
our schedule gets
pushed back any further,
火影様に大目玉をくらうぞ。
the Lady Hokage will have our hides.
そうそう！
お肉を　たっぷり頼むぞ！
Yeah, I want lots of meat in there!
おい　２人とも
しっかり食っておけよ！
And you two, eat up!
腹が減っては　戦はできんぜよ。
You can't wage war on
an empty stomach.
こいつらの要求なんか
聞くこたぁねえぞ～！
Don't bother listening to
these guys' demands!
早く
やっつけちまってくれってば～！
Just hurry up and beat 'em!
みんな　のんきに
カレー食べてるわよ。
No one's listening.
They're eating curry.
ヤマト隊長たち　本体を
救出するつもりあるのかしら？
Do you think Captain Yamato
and the rest
will come to rescue you?
あるに決まってんだろ！
Of course!
上忍の高等忍術にかかりゃ→
And in the face of
a jonin's superior ninjutsu,
単細胞の俺の　更に　分身なんざ
簡単にやられちまうってばよ！
simple-minded clones like you
will be easily destroyed!
いったい　どんな作戦で来るか…。
I wonder what kind
of tactic he'll use?
誰かが飛び込んだのか？
Did someone just dive in?
あれは…。
That's...
な　なんで泳いでんだ！？
W-Why is he swimming?
忍なんだから　海の上
走って来ればいいのに。
He's a shinobi.
Why doesn't he run across
the surface of the water?
おもしれえ！　ガイ先生だって上忍だ
何かあるんだってばよ！
Interesting!
Guy Sensei is also a jonin.
They have something up
their sleeves.
よう！　ナルトの諸君。
Hey, Naruto my boy!
気をつけろよ。　死角から
何か出てくるかも。
You'd better watch out.
Something might appear
from a blind spot.
わからんのか？
裸一貫の　俺様のメッセージを。
Don't you get it?
What this naked body
of mine is telling you?
武器も小細工も　ないわ！
I have neither weapons
nor tricks up my sleeve!
ノープランでやって来たのかよ！？
この人…。
He seriously came here
without a strategy?
俺たちの要求は
聞き入れてくれるんだろうな？
I hope you're gonna agree
to our demands?
そんなものは　こざかしい！
That's so pretentious!
とぉっ！
The sound of flesh hitting flesh.
肉体と肉体が　ぶつかり合い→
Feeling it resonate through your bones
and hearing it deep in your inner ear.
その骨伝導によって
互いの心を知るのがいちばん。
That's the best way to
understand one another!
お前たちの思いを　この俺に
ぶつけてみろ！
So come at me and let me
feel your thoughts!
なんで
こんな人をよこすんだよ…。
Why'd they have to send
a guy like this?
さっ　来い！
Come on!
わっしょい！
ナイス！　ゲキマユ先生！
Way to go, Bushy Brow Sensei!
Hurry and untie me!
早く　ロープほどいてくれ！
どっせ～い！
え～っ！？
Again!
Huh?!
一発でも食らったら
消滅しちゃう。
If even one blow hits us,
we'll be extinguished!
しまった！
Damn it!
はっ！
はは～い！
うぉっ！
待て～い！
Hold it!
そりゃ　そりゃ　そりゃ　そりゃ～！
There! There! There! There!
ん？
うぉ～っ！
やっほ～っ！
（２人）ハイ　ハイ　ハイ！　しゃっ！
– Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
《いいぞ　そうこなくっては》
Looking good. That's the way.
本気でいくぞ～！
This time, I'm serious!
え～っ！
とぉ～っ！
あいや～　そりゃ～！
Take this!
That was dangerous!
やばい！　やばい！
死ぬかと思ったってば！
I thought I was going to die!
はぁ～…。
So you're safe.
ほう　無事だったか。
Returning to the ship was smart.
船に戻ったのは　正解だ。
I can't fight seriously on
board a ship either.
俺とて　船の上で本気で
戦うわけにはいかんからな。
フンッ　俺たちが　ただ漠然と海の上を
逃げていたと思ってんのか？
Did you think we were
simply running away?
ん？
海の上で　ガイ先生が→
If we could induce Guy Sensei
to unleash a big attack at sea,
大技を出すように仕向け
船に戻れば…。
and somehow we counter it
and get back to the ship...
Naturally, Guy Sensei would follow us.
当然　ガイ先生も追って来る！
And just about then,
ちょうどその頃　ガイ先生の
大技の余波が…。
the waves from the after-shock
of your attack would...
ぬおっ。　うぉっ…。
This swaying...
Make it stop!
この揺れ止めてくれ。
俺の三半規管が…。　ウプッ。
My inner ear!
せっかくいただいたカレーが。　ウグッ。
Just when I ate my curry.
ウモモ…。
After going on that rampage,
さんざん大暴れしたあげく
状況は不利。
the end result is that he put us
at a disadvantage.
あの人
作戦の意図わかってんのか。
Does he even know the purpose
of our strategy?
（ヤマト）船上生活のストレスを発散
したかったんじゃないですか。
Maybe he just wanted to release
some pent-up stress of being at sea.
あっ　捕まった。
Oh, he’s been caught.
Looks like I've been caught.
こりゃ一本とられた。
人質が増えただけじゃねえか。
All you did was give them
another hostage.
ガイ先生　ヤマト隊長たちが→
Okay, Guy Sensei,
tell us Captain Yamato’s strategy.
どんな作戦でくるのか
話してもらおうか。
Well, I rushed in on impulse.
ウム　勝手に
飛び出してきちゃったからな。
作戦の内容は　な～んも知らん。
So I know nothing regarding the details
of the strategy.
フフッ。
何しに来たんだってばよ！
Then why did you come here?!
よっ。
すごい　すごい。
Wow! That's amazing!
大漁　大漁。
That's a huge fish!
Should we salt and grill it?
塩焼きかな？
フライにしてもおいしそう。
Fried would be good too.
ほい。　煮つけもいいかな。
Here.
Stewed would be good too.
そっち　ちゃんと見張れよ。
見張ってるわよ。
Hey! Keep guarding that side!
I am!
うわぁ　なんだこりゃ！
What the hell is this?!
グッ　見えない。
I can't see!
うわぁ～。
Oh, Ninja Art, Animal Suit Jutsu...
Get it?
あっ　忍法着ぐるみの術。
な～んてな。
もうちょっと真剣に
作戦考えてくれってばよ。
Couldn't you come up with
a more serious strategy?!
とっつかまえろ。
Capture them!
ヤマト隊長。
今のうちにロープを。
Captain Yamato!
Untie the rope while
we have the chance!
《チッ　鳥の群れは
ヤマト隊長が船に乗り込み→
Damn! Those gulls were just
a diversion to allow
Captain Yamato to get on board
and activate his jutsu.
術を発動するまでの
目くらましだったのか》
シャ～ッ！
やっと自由の身だってばよ。
Free at last!
But it still doesn’t feel like we are.
でも　なんか今ひとつ
開放感に欠けるような。
全員人質という状況に
変わりねえじゃねえか。　バ～カ。
Because stupid, as it is now,
we're all hostages.
本体に向かってバカとはなんだ。
お前らバカの分身じゃねえか　バカ。
How dare you call
the real me "stupid"?!
You clones are the stupid ones, stupid!
たぶん　バカだけ
本体に残ったんじゃねえの。
Stupidity is probably all
that's left inside you.
なっ　なんだと？
まあ待て　ナルト。
W-What did you say?
Hold on, Naruto.
あいつらの要求をな　のんで
やってもいいんじゃないのか？
Why don't just give in
to their demands?
W-What're you saying,
Bushy Brow Sensei?
何言ってんだよ　ゲキマユ先生。
I can understand where
they're coming from.
あいつらの気持も
わからんではない。
Until now, they've worked tirelessly
without complaint.
今まで無償で
お前のために働いてきたんだ。
Isn't it only fair to listen
to what they want?
だったら少しくらい願いを
聞いてやってもいいだろう　なぁ。
Right?
あ…　俺ら少しでも
わかってもらえたら→
Yeah, we're just asking for
a little understanding here.
Our demands aren't important if...
要求なんか別に…。
ふざけんな。
Stop messing around.
なんで俺がこいつらの要求を
のまなきゃならねえんだよ。
Why should I listen to any
of their demands?!
I'm the real Naruto!
俺が本体だぞ。　本体は親も同然。
I'm like their parent!
子供が親の言うことを聞くのは
当たり前だろうが。
And kids are supposed to
obey their parents!
そんなもんいつ決めた？
こうなったら我々は→
When did you decide that?
Fine! Then we demand the same rights
as the real Naruto!
本体を持ち回りにして平等に
そのリーダーとしての権利を要求する。
We demand equal turns
to be the leader!
Clones are clones!
分身は分身だ。
本体になんかなれるかよ。
There's no way
you can be the real me!
コピーの分際で何言いやがる。
You're just copies!
So don't get cocky!
ナルト　お前　言いすぎだぞ。
Naruto! That's uncalled for!
Whose side are you on,
Bushy Brow Sensei?!
ゲキマユ先生ってば
どっちの味方だよ！
俺はナルトの味方だ。
I am on your side, Naruto!
もう一度あいつらを…
お前自身を　よく見てみろ。
Take a good look once more
at them, at yourself!
ほれ！
♪～
俺は　あんなにメソメソしてねえし
うぬぼれてもいねえ。
I'm not a wimp,
and I'm not conceited like that!
ニヤニヤ舞い上がってもいねえし→
I don’t go around grinning
all the time
ましてや　ぜってえ　オネエじゃねえ！
and I'm totally not like that!
ナルト！
Naruto!
ヤマト隊長　せっかく俺のために
作戦立ててくれたのに→
Captain Yamato, I'm sorry.
After you planned
a strategy just to save me.
悪い　やっぱ俺のやり方で
いかせてもらうってばよ。
But I've got to do this my own way!
まだ分身頼りかよ。
Is he still relying on clones?
だって　分身いなきゃ
螺旋丸も　うてないし。
Well, he can't use Rasengan
without clones.
言ってろ。　４人ぽっち。
Keep talking, you four!
１００人も出せば
あっという間に終わりだ。
If I summon a hundred more,
it'll be over in a jiffy for you.
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
いくぞ　分身ども！
Here we go, clones!
あぁ…　あぁ…　うわぁ！
ぐはっ！
いつまでも　お前がお前だっていう
保証はないんだよ。
There's no guarantee that
you're going to be you forever.
いつ自分が取って代わられたって
不思議はないだろう。
There's nothing strange in
being taken over at any time.
俺たちは　このチャンスを
ずっと待っていたんだ。
This is the chance
we've been waiting for.
だから　お前の無茶な要求にも
耐えてきた。
That's why we listened to
all your ridiculous requests.
これからは　俺たちが　お前だ！
From now, we are you.
バ…　バカ！
本体の俺がやられたら→
S-Stupid!
If I die, then so do you!
分身の　お前たちだって。
果たして
本当に　お前が本体なのかな？
That's if you are indeed
the real Naruto.
試してみようじゃないか
どっちが本体か。
Let's test it out
and see who is the real Naruto.
うわぁ～っ！
イテテ…。
うわぁ～！
いや　なにも
そこまで驚かなくたって。
Hey, there’s no reason
to get so surprised.
え！？　あれ　武器は？
What? Where are the weapons?
お前たち　ストライキして→
Weren't you guys on strike and
going to steal my identity?
俺から本体を
奪おうとしてたんじゃ…。
なに訳わかんねえこと
言ってんだってばよ。
What kind of nonsense is that?
それに　確か分身は４人いたはず。
And I'm sure there were four clones.
だから～
さっきマストの滑車が落ちてきて→
So earlier, the pulley from
the mast came falling
分身の１体が
お前をかばって消えちまった。
and one of your clones shielded you
with his body and disappeared.
俺を　かばった？
He protected me?
覚えてねえのかよ？
Don't you remember?
((お前ら…　俺と本体…。
You... Me... The real Naruto.
(我々は本体の権利をも要求する))
We demand the same rights
as the real Naruto!
あれは　分身が見てた夢。
So that was a clone's dream.
分身が解けて
その情報が俺の中に入って→
And when the clone was released,
the details were left inside me
それが現実とゴチャゴチャになったのか。
and got mixed up with reality.
お！
ようやく術を解いてくれるのか？
Hey! Are you finally going
to release the jutsu?!
あぁ　ご苦労さん。
Yeah, good work.
解！
Release!
♪～
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokyuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
dance dance dance to you
just just just to you
akai itode tsunagacchattenda
We're connected by the Red String of Fate
dareka ga dareka wo damashite achichi
Somebody is doing something
burning hot by deceiving somebody
sonna de iinoka?
Are you OK with that?
ore wa chigauze baka ni sunjanee
I'm not like them. You don't know the first thing about me
kitanai kirei giragira no sora
The dirty, beautiful sky glitters
antanimo mieterunokai?
Can you see it too?
hageshiku aishi aisareta koto wa arunokai?
Have you ever loved, and been loved, passionately?
ore to anta no kizuna wa dounatterundai?
What's become of our bond?
c'mon!
haato dokyun de bachibachi sunzen
My heart is thumping and about to explode
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! aini mudawanee!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Love is it!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Next Episode
＜季節のご飯が
大好きな豆助＞
Whe war will begin soon.
Lady Tsunade, I know you’re planning to send me
≪は～い　お待たせ
できたわよ
to the frontlines as a commander.
A slight error in judgment could result in my friends dying.
Do I really have the power right now
＜　それは　秋の到来をしみじみと→
to command everyone and hold their lives in my hands?
Of course, I’m indecisive.
しみじみ～と実感できる
炊き込みご飯＞
Next on Naruto Shippuden: "The Closed Route"
The Closed Route
Go. There’s a mission that’s just right for you.
＜　その名は…＞